我們看戲  看厭了虛偽的表情
We've become bored with watching actors give us phony emotions.
看厭了花巧的特技
We're tired of pyrotechnics and special effects.
楚門的世界...
While the world he inhabits...
可以說是假的
Is, in some respects, counterfeit
楚門本人卻半點不假
There's nothing fake about Truman himself
這節目沒有劇本  沒有提場
No scripts   No cue cards.
未必是傑作  但如假包換
It isn't always Shakespeare, but it's genuine.
是一個人一生的真實記錄
It's a life.
我捱不住了
I'm not going to make it.
你自己去吧  不要等我
You're going to have to go on without me.
老兄  怎可以?
No way, mister.
你即使一拐一拐
You're going to the top of this mountain,
也得爬上山頂
broken legs and all.
觀眾通宵收看  視他如良友
We find many viewers leave him on all night for comfort.
你發神經  知道嗎?
You're crazy, You know that?
我的生活不分公私
Well, for me, There is no difference between a private life and a public life.
"真人表演"是我全部的生活
My life...is my life, is the Truman show.
"真人表演"是典範的生活
The Truman show Is...A lifestyle.
是高尚的生活
It's a noble life.
美滿的生活
It is...a truly blessed life.
我還有什麼不知道  你說吧
Yeah, tell me something I don't know.
好  你要答應我一件事
All right. Promise me one thing, though.
如果未到達山頂  而我死去的話
If I die before I reach the summit
你要把我當作糧食
You'll use me as an alternative source of food.
好噁心
Ew. Gross.
內容真真實實  原原本本
It's all true. It's all real.
各位所見的  絕無虛假
Nothing here is fake. Nothing you see on this show is fake.
有的只是調控
It's merely controlled.
吃掉我  我命令你
Eat me, damn it. That's an order.
也許只吃你喜歡的肚腩
Maybe just your love handles.
我有肚腩?
I have love handles?
有  小肚腩
Yeah. Little ones.
楚門  你快遲到了
Truman, You're going to be late.
知道了
Ok
早安
Good morning.
Morning. Morning.
假如再碰不見你們
Oh, and in case I don't see you,
祝你早 午 晚都安
Good afternoon, Good evening, And good night.
- 早安  楚門  - 早安  史賓沙
- Morning.  - Morning, spencer.
阿冥  不准
Hey, Pluto.No, no, no. Get down.
阿冥不會咬你
He won't hurt you.
我知道  但仍然怕
Get down. Ha ha. I know.It's just me.
來  阿冥
Come on, Pluto.
哦
Ohh
老天
Holy cow.
那是什麼
What is it?
現在新聞簡報
Here's a news flash just in.
一架客機飛經桃源島上空時
An aircraft in trouble began shedding parts
發生故障  零件脫落
As it flew over Seahaven just a few moments ago.
幸好沒有擊中人  各位可好?
Wow. Luckily, No one was hurt. But, hey, How do you feel today?
正打算搭飛機?
You thinking of flying somewhere?
- 不  - 不? 那就好了
- Nope. - No? Good.
行船走馬三分險  何況搭飛機
This is classical clive with classical drive, So why don't you forget about the perils of flying,
現在播段音樂  幫你寧神鎮驚
Settle back, and let this music calm you down.
一本"狗迷"  麻煩你
Dog fancy, please.
多謝
Thank you very much.
老嶽  一份報紙  還有...
Ahh! Give me a paper there, will you, earl?
我要一本  太太愛看時裝雜誌
Oh, and, uh... One of these for the wife. Loves her fashion mags.
- 還要什麼? 楚門  - 統統齊全
- Will that be all for you, Truman?  - That's the whole kit and caboodle.
再見
Catch you later. Ok.
漢克
Hey. Hank.
早安  楚門
Morning, Truman.
- 早安  楚門  - 你們好
- Good morning, Truman. - Hey, how are you, guys?
- 今天天氣很好 是嗎?  - 天天都這樣好
- Beautiful day, Isn't it?  - Oh. Always.
- 太太可好?  - 好  你們的呢?
- Oh, and how's your lovely wife?  - Good, good. How about yours?
好極了
Oh, couldn't be better.
嗯 跟你聊聊天挺好 楚門
Um, nice talking to you, Truman.
彼此彼此
You, too. Fine, fine, fine.
我們要趕時間
We must go now.
肯幫我買保險嗎?
Hey, think about that policy, huh?
買一送一  孿生子有特惠
Ok, that's 2 for 1. That's a good deal. Doppelganger special.
老友  進去嗎?
Hey, fellas. You going in?
- 請  - 不  你先
- Hey. Go ahead. - No, you first, Please.
謝謝
Thanks
I'm not that anxious to get there.
我想查一查菲濟的電話
Yes, hello. Could I have directory assistance for Fiji, please?
菲濟群島
Fiji Islands.
楚門  你看 (桃源獲選全球最佳居所)
Truman, Did you see this?
太太  抱歉 他如果昏迷就不能投保
Ha! Uh, I'm sorry, ma'am. If...if he's in a coma, He's probably uninsurable.
對  菲濟  麻煩你
Hello, Yes. Uh, Fiji, please.
登記冊有沒有一位叫羅蘭的人
Do you have a listing for lauren Garland?
沒有嗎?
Nothing listed?
叫施維亞的呢?
Ok. Do you have a Sylvia Garland?
開頭字母是S
"S" for Sylvia.
沒有
Nothing?
謝謝
Ok. Thank you.
- 勞倫斯 - 楚門
- Lawrence. - Hey, Burbank.
維園有一宗保險
Got a prospect in Wells Park
我要你去成交
I need you to close.
維園?
Wells park?
在港島那裡?
On, uh...Harbor Island?
還有別處嗎?
You know another one?
不行
Well, I can't do it.
我要見牙醫  我的牙齒要補
I, uh, have an appointment. Dentist. Or... Yeah.
你賣不夠保險 要補的不僅是牙齒
You're going to lose a lot more than your teeth if you don't meet your quota.
公司打算月底裁員
They're making cutbacks at the end of this month.
裁員?
Cutbacks?
這宗生意你一定要做成
Yeah. Now, you need this.
順便去吹吹海風  對你有益
Besides, a half hour across the bay, a little sea air...Would do you good.
謝謝
Hey, thanks.
渡輪還沒開出?
Hello. Ferry still here, huh?
我以為錯過了
Thought I might have missed it.
單程還是來回?
One-way or return?
來回
Return.
你的票
There you go, sir.
可以幫你嗎?
Do you need any help, sir?
不用管我了  我沒事
You go ahead. I'll be fine.
親愛的
Hi, honey.
超級市場有贈品  看
look what I got free at the checkout.
叫"廚師良伴"
It's a chef's pal.
剁 磨 削  一物多用
It's a dicer, grater, peeler all in one.
不會鈍  可以用洗碗碟機洗
Never needs sharpening, Dishwasher safe.
真神奇
Wow. That's amazing.
楚門
Truman
剪漏了一塊
You missed a spot.
老天
Oh, jesus.
爽
這才算是啤酒
That is a beer.
馬龍  我想離開
You know, I'm thinking about getting out, Marlon.
離開? 離開什麼?
Yeah? Out of what? off this island.
離開我的工作  離開桃源島
Out of my job, Out of Seahaven. off this island.
你想辭工? 為什麼?
Out. Out of your job? What the hell's wrong with your job?
你的工作舒舒服服 只處理文件
You have a great job, Truman. You have a desk job.
我很羡慕
I'd kill for a desk job.
到你
Here you go.
想改行做雜貨?
You should try stocking vending machines for a living.
- 不想 - 雜貨夠刺激
- No, thanks. - Now, there's excitement.
你從沒興趣到外面走走?
Don't you ever get antsy? Itchy feet?
走到哪裡?
Where's there to go?
菲濟
Fiji.
菲濟在哪裡? 近佛羅里達?
Where the hell's Fiji? Near Florida?
看見嗎?
See here?
我們在這裡
Yeah. This is us...
繞個圈...
And all the way around here...
菲濟
Fiji.
再走遠一點  就回來
You can't get any further away before you start coming back.
菲濟有些島嶼是沒有人到過的
You know, there are still islands in Fiji where no human being has ever set foot.
那麼  你打算幾時去?
So, when are you going to go?
要去  並不簡單
It's not that simple.
需要錢 籌備
It takes...money, planning.
不能說走就走
I can't just up and go.
對
Right.
但我會去  一定會
I'm going to do it. Don't worry about that.
公司很快派花紅
Bonus time is just around the corner.
來喝杯酒嗎?
Hey, you coming for a drink?
今晚不行
No. I can't tonight.
似乎快有風暴  劃回去吧
I don't like the look of that weather, son. I think we should head back.
- 爸  多劃一會  - 應該回去了
- Oh, no, dad. Not yet. - No, come on. We should go back.
多劃一會嘛
A bit farther. Listen...Please?
好的
Ok.
耶
Yes.
爸!
Daddy!
像只落湯雞  去過哪裡?
You're soaked. Where have you been?
如果籌到八千元...
I figure if we can scrape together 8,000...
- 每次跟馬龍玩完後... - 就能夠到處旅行一年
- Every time you and Marlon get together... - We can bum around the world for a year on that.
然後打回原形  不名一文
And then what, Truman? We'd be where we were 5 years ago.
你不現實得像個少年
You're talking like a teenager.
也許我的心境像少年
Well, maybe I feel like a teenager.
我們要供房子
We have mortgage payments, Truman.
又要供車  怎丟得下?
We have car payments. What, we're just going to walk away from our financial obligations?
會好刺激
It would be an adventure.
我們不打算生兒育女嗎?
I thought we were going to try for a baby.
還不夠刺激?
Isn't that enough of an adventure?
兒女可遲點生  我想出外走走
That can wait. I want to get away
見見世面  闖新天地!
See some of the world
你想要成為探險家嗎?
Honey, you want to be an explorer?
這種衝動誰都有過
This'll pass.
但遲早會明白不切實際
We all think like this now and then.
先脫掉濕衫褲  好不好?
Let's get you out of these wet clothes, hmm?
上床吧
Come to bed.
你是看不到滴  每逢上床的時候
You never see anything anyway. They always...
鏡頭必定移開  播放音樂
Turn the camera and play music and...
風吹簾動  觀眾什麼都看不見
You know, the wind blows in, and the curtains move, and you don't see anything.
- "狗迷"  麻煩你  - 好的
- Dog fancy, please. - Dog fancy
謝謝
Thank you.
老嶽  報紙
Paper, Earl, please. Paper.
順便要份時裝雜誌
Oh...I might as well pick one of these up.
- 給太太的  - 少不得
- for the wife?  - She's got to have them.
- 還要什麼? - 統統齊全
- Anything else, Truman? - That's the whole ball of wax.
再見
Catch you later.
好的
Ok.
爸?
Dad?
你們幹什麼?
Ohh! Hey, what are you doing?
究竟...
Hey! What the...
讓開!
Get out of the way!
截停他們!
Stop them!
Stop those people!
停!
Stop! Stop!
打開門! 停車!
Hey! Open the doors! Somebody stop the bus!
停下巴士!
Stop the bus!
誰來幫忙停下它!
Somebody stop it!
Somebody stop the bus!
停下巴士!
Stop the bus!
一點也不出奇
It doesn't sound insane at all, Truman.
我經常見到你爸爸的影子
I see him 10 times a week in a hundred different faces.
上星期四  我差點抱錯了人
I almost hugged a perfect stranger in the salon last thursday.
我明明見到爸爸
It was dad.
他樣子像個流浪漢
I swear. Dressed like a homeless man.
你知道最不可思議的是什麼嗎?
And you know what else Was strange?
一個商人和一個拉著狗的女人 突然出現  把他推上巴士
A businessman and a woman with a little dog came out of nowhere and forced him onto a bus.
市政局早應該驅逐流浪漢
Well, it's about time they cleaned up the trash downtown
否則本地也會亂七八糟
Before we become just like the rest of the country.
爸爸的屍體一直打撈不到
They never found Dad's body.
- 或者...  - 別亂想了
- Maybe somehow... - Oh, god.
我見到的難道是他的孿生兄弟?
I'm telling you, if it wasn't him, it was his twin.
爸爸有沒有兄弟?
Did dad have a brother?
你很清楚爸爸是個獨子
Truman, you know perfectly well. That your father was an only child
像你一樣
Just like you.
楚門... 你爸爸淹死  你覺得內疚
Now, sweetie... You're just feeling bad because of what happened
你把船向風暴駛去
You sailing off into that storm.
但我從來沒有怪你
But I've never blamed you, Truman...
一向都不怪你
And I don't blame you now.
楚門?
Truman?
你在地下室幹什麼?
What are you doing down here?
修理剪草機
Fixing the mower.
今天我見到爸爸
Saw my father today.
我知道
I know.
你媽媽打過電話來
Your mother called.
你不應該觸動她的傷心事
You really shouldn't upset her like that.
找我幹什麼?
Did you want... What did you want?
我煮了通心粉
I made macaroni.
我不餓
I'm not hungry.
我們應該扔掉那剪草機
You know...You really ought to throw out that mower.
買一部愛奇牌剪草機吧
Get one of those new Elk rotaries.
他在幹什麼?
What's he doing?
她雖然被帶走 但他對她念念不忘
See, they got rid of her, but they couldn't erase the memory.
不忘誰?
The memory of who?
(桃源學院)
[trumpet playing]
- 你沒事吧?
- Whoa. Ow
- 你沒事吧?  - 你好
- Excuse me. - Hi. Hi.
- 我撞倒你 對不起  - 不要緊
- I'm so sorry I fell on you like that. - It's Ok.
-我失魂落魄 -不要緊
- I'm just...I've been such a klutz all day. - It's all right.
我必定扭傷了腳踝
Sprained this ankle. Oh, my goodness.
摔在你身上  對不起
Oh, I'm so sorry. I'm so sorry to fall on you like that.
不要緊  不用介意
Oh, that's all right. Don't worry about it.
- 我叫美露   - 我叫楚門
- I'm Meryl. - Hi. I'm Truman.
幸會
Hey. Nice to meet you.
楚門  你太用功了
Truman, you've studied enough.
我要記熟
No. I got to commit this to memory.
一起去喝杯冰凍啤酒
Come on, Truman, one ice-cold brewski.
來吧
Come on.
你要小心  你抄我 我錯你就錯
Come on. You're going to have to copy off me, so be careful.
我知道
I know it.
楚門  你比我老實  再見
No? You're a better person than I am.
再見
See you later.
Ok. Bye.
再見  傻瓜
Bye. See you later, loser.
晚上好（日語）
Konnichi-wa.
你說什麼?
What?
你在學日文
Oh. You take japanese.
對了
Oh, yes. Yeah.
你叫羅蘭  對嗎?
Lauren, right?
上面寫著...
It's on the...
羅蘭  對
Lauren. Right, right.
我叫楚門
I'm Truman Burbank.
我知道
Yeah...I know.
他們不准我跟你交談
You know, I'm not allowed to talk to you.
真的?
Really?
可以明白  我是個危險人物
Yeah. Well, I can understand that. I'm a pretty dangerous character.
對不起  我作不了主
I'm sorry. It's not up to me.
女兒家當然要小心
A girl's got to be careful.
你有男朋友  對不對?
You have a boyfriend, right?
不是因為男朋友
No, it's not that.
因為跟我一起那小姐?
Was it Meryl, that girl that was with me?
我們... 只是普通朋友
We're not...we don't...we're not...we're just...we're friends.
不是因為她
It's nothing like that.
因為我的樣子不合眼緣?
It's how I look? Not your type?
不
No.
我喜歡你的襟章
I like your pin.
我自己也不知道
I was wondering that myself.
你願不願意... 可能的話...
Mmm. Would you want to...Maybe possibly...
陪我上街  去吃薄餅?
Sometime go out for some pizza or something?
星期五?
Like, friday?
- 星期六?  - 我不能
- Saturday?  - I can't.
星期日? 星期一? 星期二?
Sunday? Monday? Tuesday?
明天是期終考試
We have finals tomorrow.
我知道
Yeah, I know.
我們現在不去  以後沒有機會
If we don't go now, It won't happen.
明白嗎?
Do you understand?
你認為怎樣?
So, what do you want to do?
不要把手伸出車外
Please keep your hands inside the car!
這是我最喜歡吃薄餅的地方
This is my favorite Pizza place.
東尼!  來個大薄餅 多加點水藻
Tony! One large, extra plankton.
我們時間無多  他們快來了
We have so little time. They're going to be here any minute.
- 誰? - 他們不想我和你交談
- Who are? - They don't want me talking to you.
那就別交談好了
Then don't talk.
他們來了
They're here.
- 楚門 - 他們想怎樣?
- Truman. - What do they want?
聽我說  人人都清楚你的一切
Listen to me. Everybody knows about you. Everybody knows everything you do.
人人都在假裝!明白嗎?
They're pretending, Truman. Do you understand? Everybody's pretending.
- 羅蘭 我不明白...  - 不 我不是羅蘭
- Lauren, I don't know...  -No, my name's not Lauren.
我叫施維亞
It's Sylvia. My name's Sylvia.
- 施維亞? - 是的
- Sylvia? - Yeah.
羅蘭  你又來了
Lauren, sweetheart, Not again.
等等  你是誰?
Hey, wait a minute. Who are you?
- 她的爸爸  - 什麼?
- I'm her father  - What?
- 我沒見過他
- I've never even Seen him before.
乖女兒  我們走吧
Honey, please.
別信他  我說的話都是真的!
He's lying. Truman, please, Don't listen to him. Everything I've told you is the truth.
這是假的  都是為你而設的
This, it's fake. It's all for you.
- 我不明白  - 什麼都是虛構的
- I don't understand.  - The sky and the sea, everything...it's a set.
是做戲  人人在看你  別信他
It's a show. Everybody's watching you. Please don't listen to him.
他會騙你 小心 他們在觀看我們
He's gonna lie to you. They're watching us now.
- 究竟什麼事?  - 精神分裂
- What's going on?  - Schizophrenia. She has episodes.
- 求求你 不要!  - 我們已經儘量醫她
- Please. Oh, no! - We've tried Everything.
別擔心 你不是第一個
Don't worry. You're not the first.
- 不要聽他的  - 她把所有男朋友都帶來這裡
- Don't listen to him. - She brings all her boyfriends down here.
他在說什麼? 楚門  他在騙你
What's he saying? Truman, he's lying!
你要逃出去  逃出去找我
Get out of here. Come and find me.
我們在學校再見
I'll see you at school
我們要搬去菲濟
Fiji. We're moving to Fiji.
菲濟?
Fiji?
施維亞!
Sylvia!
他為什麼不跟她去菲濟?
Why didn't he just follow her to Fiji?
他媽媽患了大病
His mother got sick, really sick.
他孝順  不忍心離開 也許太孝順了
He couldn't leave her. He's kind. Maybe he's too kind.
他失去羅蘭不久  就娶了美露
I can't believe he married Meryl on the rebound.
對不起
Excuse me.
我們已有那段劇情的影帶
Come on, sal. We've already got this on the greatest hits tape.
可以借給我嗎?
Can I borrow that?
(怎樣收場?)
有幾分相像  但不全像
Close, but no cigar.
世外桃源又一天
And it's another beautiful day in paradise, folks
但大家要記著系上安全帶
But don't forget to buckle up out there in radio land.
等候提示 等候提示
Wait for the cue. Wait for the cue.
準備出動
Stand by, one.
他沿史超活道西行  臨記準備
He's heading west on stewart.
90秒後  他會到達
Stand by, all extras. He'll be on you in about 90 seconds.
記得放小狗出來
Props, make sure the coffee's hot.
他轉入蘭嘉士打廣場
Ok, he's making his turn onto Lancaster Square.
天  他差點撞倒人 哪裡出問題了 更改波頻
Oh, my god. He nearly hit her. Something's wrong. Change frequencies.
抱歉  我們忙中有錯
Ouch. Sorry about that, folks.
剛才無意中播放了員警電臺
I guess we picked up a police frequency or something. It sometimes happens, And it can drive you crazy.
現在是賈禮金曲時間
Ok, it's classical clive back in here,
我們為你準備了精彩的音樂
And we've still got some great music up ahead,
但大家記緊 扣好安全帶
But hey, don't forget to buckle up.
小心駛得萬年車  出色的司機是安全的司機
Remember safety. A good driver is a safe driver.
安全的司機又是什麼呢?
A safe driver is what? Yes.
(驅逐流浪漢 桃源島長老忍無可忍)
早上好
Morning, ma'am.
這方法好
I love that idea.
很不賴 是嗎?
It's pretty cool, Isn't it?
是的  我喜歡
Yeah, I love it.
有何貴幹?
Can I help?
我約見了基寶企業
Yeah. I have an appointment at Gable Enterprises.
不可能
That's impossible.
- 什麼事? - 沒什麼
- What's happening? - Nothing.
說  什麼事?
Just tell me what's happening.
請離開  現在正裝修
Got to go, sir. We're remodeling.
不是  他們是什麼人?
No, you're not. What are those people doing back there?
不關你事...
It's none of your business.
你不說  我去報警
If you don't tell me what's happening, I'll report you!
你擅闖他人地方!
You're trespassing.
搞定
Right.
馬龍!
Marlon!
楚門  什麼事?
Truman. What are you doing here?
我想說句話
I gotta talk to you.
我現在沒有空
It's a bad time, Ok? I'm way behind.
有些不尋常的事  很不尋常
I'm onto something, Marlon. Something big.
你面色發青
You Ok? You look like shit.
- 我可能惹上麻煩 - 什麼麻煩?
- I think I'm mixed up in something. - Mixed up in what?
很難解釋  總之千奇百怪
There's no point trying to explain it, but a lot of strange things have been happening.
升降機裡面有人  卻沒有牆
The people on the elevator. There was no backing on it.
我看過去  看到人
I looked out. There was people there.
我上班途中  聽收音機
And on the radio on the way to work,
我一舉一動  收音機直接播放
It starts following me along, talking about everything that I'm doing.
- 明白嗎? - 你想像力太豐富了
- You know what I mean? - Truman, look, this is one of your fantasies.
- 這事跟我爸爸有關 - 你爸爸?
- I think this is about my dad. - Your dad?
他可能依然活著
I think he's alive.
之後再慢慢跟你說 一定有人在跟蹤我
Yeah. I'll tell you about it later. I'm definitely being followed.
誰在跟蹤你?
Who?
很難說  似乎是普通人
It's hard to tell. They look just like regular people.
這兩個呢?
How about those two?
不知道  有可能
I don't know. Could be.
我一有突發舉動  他們就...
It's when I'm unpredictable, That's they can't...
- 有沒有事情發生? - 沒有
- Did anything happen? - No.
- 我們要離開這裡了 跟我走  行嗎?
- Mm-hmm. We gotta get out of here. - You ready to go?
- 不行 我才剛找到這份工作 - 來嘛
- No. I just came here. - Come on.
不行就不行
I told you I can't.
我們都會被炒魷魚
You're gonna get both our asses fired. You know that.
- 無所謂 大膽做 - 什麼?
- Ok, man, Let's do it. - What?
你要怎樣就怎樣 我的地盤我做主
Whatever you say. I'm game
你在說什麼?
What are you talking about?
對了  生日  一年只有一次
Yes, siree. Your birthday comes but once a year.
我可能受到別人操縱
Maybe I'm being set up for something.
你有沒有這種感覺
You ever think about that, Marlon?
好像一生都身不由己
like your whole life has been building towards something?
沒有
Mmm, no.
那年夏天  你替凱撒運雞...
When you were hauling chickens in the summer for Kaiser
離開過桃源島  到過哪裡?
What was the furthest you ever got off the island?
什麼地方都到過  但都不及這裡
Went all over. Never found a place like this, though.
看看這日落
Look at that sunset, Truman.
瑰麗無比
It's perfect.
對  上帝的傑作
Yeah. That's the big guy.
簡直鬼斧神工
Quite a paintbrush he's got.
你不要告訴別人
Just between you and me, Marlon...
我打算出外走走
I'm going away for a while.
真的?
Really?
嗯
Yeah.
小天使
Oh, little angel.
小笑彈
Oh, my little clown.
紅蘿蔔頭
Old carrot top.
最好的照片
The best photos.
應該送你回家了
We should be getting you home, mother.
等一下
Hold on a minute.
我們在偉人石像前拍的照片
Here's us at Mount Rushmore.
記得嗎? 你的爸爸當時還在生
Do you remember, Truman? When dad was still with us
車程很遠  你一直在車裡睡
That was quite a drive. You slept the whole way there.
石像看來很小
It looks so small.
回憶裡的東西總比真實的小
Things always do when you look back, darling.
你看  那是我們最快樂的一天
Oh, look, Truman. The happiest day of our lives.
看  珍 茱迪 鐘安
Oh, look. Jean, Jodie, Joanne.
她多漂亮  對不對?
Doesn't she look beautiful, Truman?
仍然漂亮
Well, she still does.
還有很多空頁可以貼小孩照片
And there's lots of pages left over for baby photos.
我希望有生之年能抱孫子
I would like to hold a grandchild in my arms before I go.
- 我們應該送你回家 - 我送她
- Angela, we really should be getting you home. - I'll take her.
不 你坐著  休息一下
No, no, no. You stay, relax.
你喜歡的節目快播映了
Enjoy yourself. Your favorite show will be coming on.
況且  美露和我有些話想說
Besides, we have something to discuss.
關於某人的生日
A certain person's birthday.
明白了
Oh, I see.
明天繼續收看"我愛露絲"
And there'll be another episode of "I love lucy" same time tomorrow.
現在是"懷舊名片"時間
But right now it's time for golden oldies.
今晚我們播映膾炙人口的
Tonight, we present The enduring, much-loved classic
"歸心似箭"
Show me the way to go home.
本片歌頌小鎮生活
A hymn of praise to small-town life,
令我們體驗到在家千日好
Where we learn that you don't have to leave home
故鄉的濃厚人情味
to discover what the world's all about, and that no one is poor who has friends.
悲歡離合  笑中有淚
Full of laughter and love, pain and sadness,
迷途知返
But ultimately redemption,
我們見證柯家的奮鬥
We share the trials and tribulations of the Abbott family.
畢朗奴飾演叔叔  感人肺腑
Note the touching performance of Ronald Brierly as Uncle Buddy.
那碗櫻桃的一幕保證各位捧腹
And that scene with the bowl of cherries is gonna have you splitting your sides with laughter all over again.
大衛 珍妮花重逢  賺人熱淚
And there'll be tears, too, when David and Jennifer are reunited.
我不再多講
But enough from me.
現在就送上錦丹村的柯家
Let's join the Abbotts in Camden Village.
楚門  謝謝你
Oh. Thank you, sweetie.
跟我到外面去  我有話想說
I need to talk to you, But let's go outside.
我很想聽  但要趕時間
Oh, sweetie, I'd love to, but I'm really late.
到哪裡去?
What's your rush?
做手術
Surgery.
升降機發生意外  新聞有報導
There was that elevator disaster downtown. It was on the news last night.
鋼纜斷了
This cable just snapped.
電梯間從十樓跌下  乘客非死則傷
This elevator, it just plummeted down 10 flights.
裡面是臨時工
The non-union workers.
那部升降機在你公司附近
Just monsters. You know, that building, it's right next door to where you are working.
幸好你沒有搭
Can you imagine if you had been in there?
否則不堪設想
It's not even worth thinking about.
有位女乘客要做切肢手術
Anyway, I have an amputation on one of the young women in that elevator.
她很年輕的  真不幸
She's very young. It's very sad.
祝我順利吧
Anyway, wish me luck.
我會疊手指  祝你順利
I'll cross my fingers for you.
對不起 請問你什麼事?
Uh, excuse me. Hi. Excuse me. May I help you?
我太太美露是這裡的護士 我有事要找她
Oh, Uh...Yes. I'm looking for my wife, Nurse Burbank.
- 很重要的事  - 恐怕不可以  她要做手術
- It's very important. - I'm afraid that's not possible. She's in pre-op.
替我傳個口訊  行嗎?
Sure. Ok, fine. Can you pass along a message?
我會試試
I'll try.
我要去菲濟 抵達後會致電給她
Can you tell her I had to go to Fiji and that I'll call her when I get there?
抵達菲濟後?
When you... When you get to Fiji?
對了
You got it.
我會告訴她
Fine. I'll tell her.
非常感激
Thank you so much.
- 對不起 - 不要緊
- Sorry. - It's Ok.
我幫你
Let me help you
他來了
He's here.
我知道
I know, Shh, shh, shh.
解剖刀
Scalpel.
我現在在右膝上...
I'm now making my primary incision...
做初步切割
Just above the right knee.
按著她
Hold her
割得恰到好處
Nicely done.
沒什麼好看  除非你是家屬
This isn't going to be pretty, Unless you are family.
你手術的確高明
It's just beautiful. Beautiful job.
讓其他人來收拾吧
I'll just let someone else tidy up here.
- 要你等  對不起 - 不要緊
- I'm sorry to keep you. - Oh, that's Ok.
可以效勞嗎?
How can I help?
一張去菲濟的機票
I would like to book a flight to Fiji.
幾時出發?
When would you like to leave?
今天
Today.
抱歉  起碼要一個月後才有位
I'm sorry. I don't have anything for at least a month.
一個月後?
A month?
現在是旺季
It's the busy season.
要不要訂位?
You want to book the flight?
不要了  我試試其他交通工具
It doesn't matter. I'll make other arrangements, Ok?
往芝加哥乘客
Last call for Chicago
所有乘客上車
All aboard
謝謝
Thank you.
風中之城芝加哥  我們來也
Windy city, here we come.
你好
Hi. Hi.
Hello.
好
Hi.
修女
Sisters.
媽媽  那個人是不是...
Hey, mom, isn't that...
看前面  乖女兒
Shh. Face the front.
各位下車  機件故障
Everybody off. We've got a problem.
對不起  小夥子
I'm sorry, son.
他的爸爸是芝加哥人  對嗎?
His father was from Chicago, wasn't he?
不  他的牙醫是佛羅里達人
No. His dentist was from Pensacola.
他爸爸是愛荷華人
His father was from Desmoines.
為什麼去芝加哥?
But how come he wants to go to Chicago?
他不想去  哪裡也不想去
He's not going to Chicago. He's not going anywhere.
只是和美露鬥氣
He has to have it out with Meryl.
楚門?
Truman?
你沒事吧?
Honey, are you Ok?
上車
Get in.
楚門?
Truman?
看
Look.
什麼?
What? Shh.
待會兒將會見到...
I predict that in just a moment...
一位太太騎著紅色單車
We will see a lady on a red bike,
然後有個人拿著鮮花
Followed by a man with flowers
跟著有架黃色甲蟲型福士
And a volkswagen beetle with a dented fender.
- 楚門  拜託. - 看
- Truman, please. - look.
太太...
Lady...
鮮花...
Flowers...
然後呢...
And...
太無聊
Truman, this is silly.
來了!
There it is! There it is!
一架黃色福士!是的!
There's that dented beetle! Yes!
知道我怎猜中嗎?
Don't you want to know how I did that?
很簡單  他們在兜圈
I'll tell you. They're on a loop.
沿著附近幾條街  不斷兜圈
They go around the block. They come back. They go around again.
他們就那樣團團轉
They just go round and round. Round and round.
我請了馬龍夫婦周日來燒烤
I invited Rita and Marlon for a barbecue on sunday.
我不會在這裡
I won't be here Sunday.
記得提醒我買炭
And I need you to remind me that we need more charcoal.
我的話你有沒有聽見?
Are you listening to a word I'm saying?
你講來講去  都要去菲濟
You're upset because you want to go to Fiji. Is that it?
去吧
Ok, Ok, go.
但應該儲幾個月的生活費才去
I think you should save for a few months and then go there.
現在滿意了沒有?
Are you happy now?
我去洗澡了
I want to go take a shower.
我們現在就去
Let's go now.
我現在可以去了
I'm ready to go now. Why wait?
坐言起行  早走早著  對不對
Early bird gathers no moss. Rolling stone catches the worm, right?
你在幹什麼?
Truman, What are you doing?
楚門!
Truman!
應該駛到哪裡去?
Where shall we go? Where shall we go?
楚門  我們去哪裡?
Truman, where are we going?
我只是漫無目的  順其自然
I don't really know. I guess I'm being spontaneous.
不得了  我順其自然起來!
Somebody help me! I'm being spontaneous!
不去菲濟了  反正開車去不到
Truman. forget Fiji. Can't very well drive to Fiji, can we?
不如去大西洋城?
What about Atlantic City?
不要去  你討厭賭博
Oh, no, you hate to gamble.
- 的確討厭  - 為什麼還去?
- That's right, I do, don't I?  - So why would you want to go there?
因為沒去過
Because I never have.
觀光就是去沒去過的地方,不是嗎?
That's why people go places, isn't it?
楚門  我想嘔吐
Truman, Truman, I think I'm gonna throw up.
我也是
Me, too.
到處都塞車
Blocked at every turn.
配合得天衣無縫  對嗎?
Beautifully synchronized, don't you agree?
連塞車你也怪我?
You're blaming me for the traffic?
不應該怪你?
Should I?
我們回家吧
Truman...Let's go home.
好  塞車可能塞幾個鐘頭
You're right. We could be stuck here for hours.
一直塞到大西洋城  回去吧
It could be like this all the way to Atlantic City. Let's go back.
我一時糊塗  不應該去
I'm sorry. I don't know what got into me.
可以駛慢一點嗎?
Can you please slow down?
可以
Yes, I can.
- 你忘記轉彎! - 我又改變主意
- Truman! Truman! That's our turnoff! - I changed my mind again.
新奧爾良這幾天應該好熱鬧不是嗎?
What's new orleans like this time of year?
是狂歡節!
Mardi gras! Whoo! Ha ha ha!
看  同一條路  一部車都沒有
Look, Meryl, same road, No cars.
像魔術一樣
It's magic. Ha ha ha!
我要下車  你的腦袋有毛病
You let me out. You're not right in the head.
你要自毀  自毀到夠
You want to destroy yourself, do it on your own.
我要人陪
I think I'd like a little company.
你明知故犯
Oh, Truman... You knew this would happen.
明知道自己不敢開車過海
You know you can't drive over water.
回家吧  你會覺得安全
Let's go home where you'll feel safe.
- 伸手過來 - 楚門
- Give me your hand. Sweetie - Truman
你轉彎
Drive.
楚門!
Truman!
不可以! 這樣做是犯法!
We shouldn't be doing this! We're breaking the law!
- 天! - 你做得到的
- Oh, my! - You can do it!
不要!
Please, don't!
- 你辦得到! - 楚門!
- You can make it! - Truman!
過了橋!  我們過了橋!
Aah! Oh, we're over! We're over the bridge! We're over the bridge!
- 過了嗎? - 我們過了橋 我們過了橋
- We're over?  - We're over the bridge. We're over the bridge.
我們過了橋!
We're over!
(山火警告：極度危險)
- 有山火 怎麼辦? - 誇大其詞  別怕
- Truman! What about that sign? - They're exaggerating. We'll be fine.
誇大其詞? 你相信嗎?
Exaggerating? Do you believe that?
著火了!
Oh, my! Oh, my! Truman, we're on fire!
只是煙霧而已
It's Ok. It's just smoke.
- 你沒事吧? - 沒事
- You Ok? - Yes.
- 想再試嗎? - 不想!
- Want to do it again? - No! Ha ha ha ha!
楚門  停車!
Truman, stop! Oh, god!
我們沒有錢!  到新奧爾良怎辦?
Oh! So, what are we going to do for money when we get to New Orleans?
我有桃源的銀行卡
I have my Seahaven Bank card.
你打算吃老本?
We're just going to eat into our savings, is that it?
一到達  我要打電話給你媽媽
I'm going to have to call your mother when we get there.
她一定擔心得要命
She's going to be worried sick.
可能受不起打擊
I don't know how she's going to take this.
又有什麼事?
What now?
(牌匾:桃源核電站)紅色警報! 紅色警報!
Red alert! This is a red alert!
核電站似乎漏輻射
Truman, it looks like a leak at the plant.
掉頭! 核電站漏輻射  要關閉
Back up! Back up! Leak at the plant. We had to shut her down.
可不可以繞路?
Is there any way around?
全區都要疏散
Whole area's being evacuated.
- 要我幫忙嗎? - 不用
- Is there anything I can do?  - No, ma'am.
- 謝謝你 - 不用客氣  楚門
- Thank you for your help. - You're welcome, Truman.
楚門
Truman.
楚門! 楚門!
Truman! Truman!
楚門...回來!
Truman...come back!
截停他!
Truman! Truman! Stop him!
楚門!
Unh! Truman!
他往出口竄去!
Head to the left!
不要走過來!
Stay away!
不要!
Unh! No!
不!
No!
已經控制好狀況了
Now in custody.
麻煩了你們  很不好意思
Thank you both so much for your help. I really appreciate it.
這次放過他  下次我們要檢控
He's lucky to be alive, ma'am. Next time, we'll have to file charges.
我明白
I understand.
- 再次謝謝你們  晚安  - 晚安
- Thanks again. Good night. - Good night.
你需要接受治療
Let me get you some help, Truman.
你有病
You're not well.
為什麼要替我生孩子?
Why do you want to have a baby with me?
你不喜歡我
You can't stand me.
不是
That's not true.
我去倒杯莫可哥給你?
Why don't you let me fix you some of this new mococoa drink?
尼加拉瓜山天然可哥煉製
All natural cocoa beans from the upper slopes of Mount Nicaragua.
不含人工糖分
No artificial sweeteners.
你在說什麼?
What the hell are you talking about?
跟誰說話?
Who are you talking to?
各種可哥中  莫可哥最好喝
I've tasted other cocoas. This is the best.
跟我們有什麼關係?
What the hell does this have to do with anything?
究竟什麼事!
Tell me what's happening!
你還問? 你自己精神崩潰
You're having a nervous breakdown, that's what happing.
你有份  對不對?
You're part of this, aren't you?
- 楚門! - 美露!
- Truman! - Meryl!
你嚇怕了我!
You...are...scaring me!
你才嚇怕了我
No, you're scaring me, Meryl.
你打算怎樣處置我?
What are you going to do?
剁? 切? 削?
Dice me? Slice me or peel me?
多種選擇!
There are so many choices!
快想想辦法!
Aah! Do something!
你說什麼?
What? What did you say?
你跟誰說話?
Who are you talking to?
我沒有說話  什麼也沒說
Nothing. I didn't say anything. I didn't say anything.
- 你有說 - 我沒有
- You said, "do something." - No, I didn't. I wasn't talking to anybody.
- 告訴我! - 我毫不知情!  停手!
- Talk to me! - I don't know anything! Please stop!
不要動!
Stay where you are!
楚門?
Truman?
謝天謝地!
Oh, thank god! Oh, thank god!
叫我怎忍受下去?
How can anyone expect me to carry on under these conditions?
完全沒有專業精神!
It's unprofessional!
不要怕
Shh, it's Ok.
沒事  不要怕
Everything's gonna be Ok.
天啊!
Oh, god!
一切都會好的
It's all gonna be fine.
我腦袋一片混亂
I don't know what to think, Marlon.
快要瘋了 但...
Maybe I'm losing my mind, but...
全世界似乎繞著我而轉
It feels like the whole world revolves around me somehow.
即是說  你自以為好重要
That's a lot of world for one man, Truman.
不是有點一廂情願嗎?
Sure that's not wishful thinking?
你感覺鬱鬱不得志?
You wishing you'd made something more out of yourself?
不得志是很正常的感覺
Come on, who hasn't sat in the john,
誰也希望躊躇滿志
Had an imaginary interview on Seahaven tonight?
誰也希望做個名人
Who hasn't wanted to be somebody?
我的意思是人人都似乎在串謀
This is different. Everybody seems to be in on it.
你七歲時  我們已經是老朋友
I've been your best friend since we were 7 years old.
讀書考試  你抄我  我抄你
The only way you and I ever made it through school was by cheating off each other's test papers.
你我的答案一模一樣
Jesus, they were identical.
我總覺得安全
But I always felt safe knowing that.
因為無論答對還是答錯
'Cause whatever the answer was,
我們都能夠一同對  一同錯
We were right together and we were wrong together.
那一晚去露營  通宵不睡
Remember when I stayed up all night in your tent
因為你要扮北極
'Cause you wanted to play north pole?
搞到我得肺炎
And I got pneumonia?
記得嗎?
You remember that?
你要向學校請了一個月的病假
You were out of school for about a month.
你我親如兄弟
You're the closest thing I ever had to a brother.
我知道...
I know that things...
你我的人生都不算順利
Haven't really worked out for either of us
離理想相當遠
like we used to dream they would.
覺得時不與我...
I know that feeling, When it's like everything's slipping away...
你無法面對現實  於是...
You don't want to believe it...
疑神疑鬼...
So you look for answers somewhere else, but...
但我肯為你這朋友  兩脅插刀
Well...the point is...I'd gladly walk in front of traffic for you.
Well...The point is, I would gladly step in front of traffic for you, Truman.
怎也不會欺騙你
And the last thing I'd ever do is lie to you.
怎也不會...
And the last thing That I would ever do...
欺騙你
Is lie to you.
你不妨想一想
I mean, think about it, Truman.
假如人人都串謀...
If everybody is in on it...
即是說  我也串謀
I'd have to be in on it, too.
我沒有串謀  因為...
I'm not in on it, Truman, because...
根本沒有這回事
There is no "it."
但有一件事你是對的
You were right about one thing, though.
什麼事?
What's that?
這場風波的起因
The thing that started all this.
我替你找到他
Yep. I found him for you, Truman.
所以我今晚來找你
That's why I came by tonight.
他必定有很多話要說
I'm sure he's got quite a story to tell.
你過去吧
Go to him.
煙霧不要太濃
Easy on the fog.
吊臂攝影機準備
Stand by, crane cam.
吊臂攝影機
Crane cam.
按攝影機三號
Button cam 3.
我一直都相信你沒遇難
I never stopped believing.
用廣角鏡  路邊攝影機八號
And wide, curb cam 8.
乖兒子!
My son! Oh!
- 要不要特寫? - 暫時不要
- Move in for a closeup? - No, no, no.
等一下
Move back and
加強配樂
Fade up music.
現在特寫
And now go in close.
這麼多年  白白過去
All those years wasted.
我會彌補你的損失
I'll make it up to you, son.
一定會
I swear.
爸爸
Dad.
厲害!
Yes!
很精彩
Bravo.
- 好艱辛的歷程 - 恭喜
- That was a really great experience. - Congratulations.
大家靜一點  留神
Ok, quiet down. Let's concentrate.
幹得好
That was good work.
開香檳慶祝
Let's get some champagne up here.
克裡斯多夫  太精彩了
Brilliant, Christof. Just brilliant.
多麼感人肺腑
It just broke my heart.
大家幹得好!  恭喜
Well done, everyone! Congratulations
(楚門喝尼加拉瓜山出產)
(由頂級可哥煉製的莫可哥)
十七億人見證他出生
1.7 billion were there for his birth.
(巨星誕生)
220個國家收看他學走路
220 countries tuned in for his first step.
舉世靜觀他初吻
The world stood still for that stolen kiss,
他與科技並肩成長
And as he grew, so did the technology.
一個人的一生 由秘密攝影網路記錄下來
An entire human life recorded on an intricate network of hidden cameras
原汁原味  一天二十四小時
And broadcast live and unedited 24 hours a day,
在全球不停直播
7 days a week to an audience around the globe.
桃源島是一個 規模空前龐大的片場
Coming to you now from Seahaven Island, enclosed in the largest studio ever constructed
從太空俯瞰地球可以看到的建築
And along with the Great Wall of China,
唯有桃源島和萬里長城
One of only two manmade structures visible from space,
光輝的第三十年  正是真人秀
Now in its 30th great year, It's the Truman show
過去一個星期
What a week it's been.
高潮迭起  好戲連場
I don't know about you...I was on pins and needles the entire time.
各位觀眾好  我是米高
Hello and good evening. I'm your host Mike Michaelson,
歡迎收看"真人表演"的 清談節目"真話"
And welcome to tru-talk, our forum for issues growing out of the show.
今晚千載難逢
But tonight, something very special indeed,
會獨家專訪 "真人表演"的創作人
A rare and exclusive interview with the show's conceiver and creator.
我們上去天網攝製 221樓的太陰室
So, come with us now as we go live to the lunar room on the 221st floor of the Omni Cam Echosphere
採訪超級電視攝製的先驅
Where we'll find the world's greatest tele-visionary
桃源島的設計者和總監
The designer and architect of the world within a world
克裡斯多夫
That is Seahaven Island... Christof.
我先代表觀眾多謝你接受專訪
Before we begin, I'd like to thank you on behalf of our audience for granting this interview.
我們知道你工作繁忙 一向作風都是儘量低調
We know how demanding your schedule is and we all know how jealously you guard your privacy.
能夠採訪你  我深感榮幸
This, sir, is indeed an honor.
不要客氣
Don't mention it.
"真人表演"最近的一波三折
Well, the catalyst for the recent dramatic events
起因是楚門的父親偷偷回去
On the show has been Truman's father, Kirk
外面的人擅闖桃源要接觸楚門
And his attempts to infiltrate the show.
但切入這話題之前 我認為也沒什麼大不了
But before we get into that, I think it's worth noting
這並不是首次有外人干擾節目
That this is not the first time someone from the outside
- 想要接觸楚門 對不對? - 但都有驚無險
- Has attempted to reach Truman, is it? - We have had close calls in the past.
楚門!上電視了!
Truman! It's television!
我終於上了"真人表演"!
Yes! Yes! I did it! I'm on the Truman show!
但歷來的擅闖事件中
But there's never been anything to compare
最近這次最嚴重...
with this most recent breach in security...
因為擅闖的人是前任演員
The first intruder to be a former cast member.
而且本來已經死了
A dead one at that.
你讓卻克復出...  是神來之筆
Gotta say, writing Kirk back in...masterstroke.
既然這場風波由卻克引起
Since Kirk started this crisis in Truman's life,
我認為解鈴還須系鈴人
I came to the conclusion that only he could end it.
楚門!
Truman! Truman!
- 不准過去! - 那裡有什麼?
- No! That's off limits! - Why? What's over there?
沒什麼  只是危險
Nothing. It's dangerous. That's all.
你要記著  有些地方不可以去
You've got to know your limitations, Truman.
當年為什麼刪除卻克這角色?
But let's remind viewers exactly why Dad was written out in the first place.
楚門長大 我們設法把他留在桃源島
As Truman grew up, we were forced to manufacture ways to keep him on the island.
我想做探險家  像麥哲倫一樣
I'd like to be an explorer, like the great Magellan.
現在世上已沒什麼好探險的
You're too late. There's really nothing left to explore.
於是  我安排卻克浸死
Finally, I came up with Kirk's drowning.
那辦法很有效  楚門從此怕水
Most effective. Truman's been terrified of the water ever since.
卻克被迫浸死  退出節目
When Kirk read the synopsis of the episode,
不消說  失望得很
He was disappointed to say the least.
於是千方百計潛回片場
I'm sure that's what caused him to break onto the set.
但你怎解釋他失蹤了二十二年?
But how do you intend to explain his 22-year absence?
失憶
Amnesia.
高明
Brilliant.
現在接聽觀眾電話
Let's take some viewer phone calls.
北卡州的卡露蓮  請說
Charlotte, North Carolina, You're on with Christof.
你好  克裡斯多夫
Uh, yeah, Hi, Christof.
你在鎮上佈置了多少部攝影機
I was wondering how many cameras you got in that town.
五千部左右
Somewhere in The vicinity of 5,000.
好多
That's A lot of cameras.
記著  我開始時只用一部
Remember, we started with just one.
他一出生就好奇  早產兩星期
He was curious from birth. Premature by 2 weeks.
就像迫不及待
Almost as if he couldn't wait to get started.
正因為他急於走出娘胎
His eagerness to leave his mother's womb
所以才獲選
Was the very reason he was the one selected
我們從六個待領養胎兒中
in competition with 5 other unwanted pregnancies,
選出楚門  因為楚門...
The casting of a show, determined by an air date
在現場直播中  準時出世
Truman was the one who arrived on cue.
楚門似乎是首名被機構
Incidentally, I believe Truman is the first child
合法領養的孩子
to have been legally adopted by a corporation.
對
That's correct.
節目帶來龐大的收益
The show has generated enormous revenues now,
相當於一個小國的年產總值
Equivalent to the gross national product of a small country.
但製作上也需要一國的人手
People forget it takes the population of an entire country to keep the show running.
因為二十四小時播放 沒廣告時間
Since the show is on 24-hours a day without commercial interruption,
收入全靠商品的選用
All those staggering revenues are generated by product placement.
對  節目上一切都是發售的
That's true. Everything on the show is for sale.
演員的服裝 食品 住屋等等
From the actor's wardrobe, food products, to the very homes they live in.
詳情請參閱真人目錄
And all of it available in the Truman catalog.
歡迎隨時來電查詢
Operators are standing by.
克裡斯多夫  請問...
Christof, let me ask you...
為什麼至今楚門還不知道
Why do you think Truman has never come close
自己活在一個什麼樣的世界?
to discovering the true nature of his world until now?
我們都接受現實
We accept the reality of the world with which we are presented.
就是那麼簡單
It's as simple as that.
海牙有觀眾打電話來  海牙?
The Hague for Christof. Hello? The Hague?
現在改接好萊塢的電話
All right, We've lost that call. Let's go to Hollywood. You're on tru-talk.
克裡斯多夫  我只想說你好陰險
Hi, Christof. I'd just like to say one thing. You're a liar And a manipulator,
你的所作所為令人噁心
And what you've done to Truman is sick!
我們都認得這把聲音 怎能忘記?
Well, we remember this voice, don't we? How could we forget?
不如改接另一個電話
Let's go to another call.
不要緊  米高
No, no, no. It's fine, Mike.
我想跟前度演員聚聚舊
I love to reminisce with former members of the cast.
施維亞...
Sylvia...
你當眾沷婦駡街  其實沒意思
As you announced so melodramatically to the world,
你以為自己曾向楚門拋眉弄眼
You think because you batted your eyes at Truman once...
打情罵俏... 曾和他一起出鏡幾分鐘
打情罵俏 曾和他一起出鏡幾分鐘
Flirted with him...Stole a few minutes of air time with him...
賣弄過自己和自己的政見
to thrust yourself and your politics into the limelight...
就以為瞭解他?
That you know him?
知道什麼才適合他?
That you know what's right for him?
有資格去評論他?
You really think you're in a position to judge him?
你有什麼權力
What right do you have to take a baby
把一個人的一生  塑造成鬧劇
And turn his life into some kind of mockery?
你一點也不覺得內疚?
Don't you ever feel guilty?
我為楚門提供一個正常的人生
I have given Truman a chance to lead a normal life.
這個你所住的世界是病態的
The world...The place you live in...Is the sick place.
桃源才是模範的世界
Seahaven's the way the world should be.
他不是演員  是囚犯
He's not a performer. He's a prisoner.
任由你擺佈
look at him! Look at what you've done to him!
他隨時可以走
He can leave at any time.
假如他稍有野心
If his was more than just a vague ambition,
假如他下定決心要查出真相
If he was absolutely determined to discover the truth,
我們無法阻止他
There's no way we could prevent him.
你不安  其實另有原因
I think what distresses you really caller
就是楚門甘願坐你所謂的監獄
is that ultimately...Truman prefers his cell, as you call it.
你錯了
That's where you're wrong.
大錯特錯  他會證明你是錯的
You're so wrong, and he'll prove you wrong.
觀眾甚少有惡評
Well, aside from The heated comments of a very vocal minority
絕大部分都說它有益世道人心
It's been an overwhelmingly positive experience.
對楚門 對觀眾  都有裨益
Yes. for Truman and for the viewing public.
克裡斯多夫  萬分感謝
Well, Christof, I can't thank you enough
感謝你百忙中接受訪問
for giving so generously of your time tonight.
現在危機已成過去
I think it's safe to say now that this crisis is behind us
楚門恢復了常態
And Truman is back to his old self,
節目會不會有新發展?
We can look forward to some exciting new developments?
未來的大事是
Well, Mike, the big news
在下一集  美露會離開楚門
Is that Meryl will be leaving Truman in an upcoming episode
楚門將會有第二春
And a new romantic interest will be introduced.
我決定將性交過程
Aha. I'm determined television's first on-air conception
首次在電視上直播
will still take place.
電視廣播即將出現新的里程碑
Well, another television milestone straight ahead.
我們已率先為大家透露
You heard it here first.
十分感謝你
It has been a singular honor and pleasure, sir.
- 克裡斯多夫 - 謝謝你  米高
- Christof  - Thank you. Thank you, Mike.
- 西文 - 什麼事?
- Hey, Simeon. - What?
他是不是看著我們?
Is he looking at us?
不得了  難道他看出了破綻?
Jesus, do you think he knows?
你好?
Hello?
我要通知克裡斯多夫
Better call Christof.
報告  畢少校
Hello? Come in, Major Burbank.
- 他故態復萌 - 天啊
- He's back to his old self. - Thank god.
好怪的貓
That's an unusual cat, my man.
謹此把本星球命名為...
I hereby...Proclaim this planet...
畢星系楚門星
Trumania of the Burbank Galaxy.
- 他要出去? - 走廊鏡頭準備
- Is he going? - Hallway camera.
免費表演一次
That one's for free.
跟貼  他行動有點快
Keep up with him. He'll move fast.
全部攝影機準備
Stand by, all house cameras.
早安!
Morning!
假如再碰不見你...
Morning. In case I don't see you...
祝你早 午 晚都安
Good afternoon, good evening, and good night.
- 午安 - 早安
- Good afternoon - Good morning.
...午安 晚安
...evening, and good night.
- 早安  楚門 - 早安  史賓沙
- Morning. - Morning, spencer.
- 你好嗎? - 讓我檢查一下
- How's it going? - Hmm, let me check.
主要功能健全
Vital signs are good.
阿冥!
Whoa, Pluto! Whoop!
- 早安  楚門 - 原來是你們
- Good morning, Truman - Oh, look who's here.
- 今天天氣很好 - 天天都這樣好
Beautiful day, isn't it? Every single day.
我們決定向你買保險
The policy...We've thought about it...and we're gonna take it.
- 說笑? - 不是說笑
- You're kidding? - No!
好極  現在就上公司簽檔吧
Great! Why don't we go up to my office right now, and we'll sign the papers?
下星期會比較方便...
Uh, next week would be much better. Next week would be better...
- 那麼到時見 - 到時見
- All right. See you guys. - Ok, bye now. See you next week.
- 約定你們了 - 一言為定
- Give me something to look forward to. - You got it.
這不是保險的事
See, this isn't about insurance.
而是生死無常的事...
This is about the great variable...
"幾時死"?
When will death occur?
可能一個星期 一個月 一年
Could be a week, a month, a year.
可能今天
Could be today.
你優哉遊哉的曬太陽
Sunbather, minding his own business,
一不留神  心臟被沙灘傘捅到
Stabbed in the heart by the tip of a runaway beach umbrella.
致命意外隨時發生  防不勝防
No way to guard against that kind of thing.
對不起
Uh, sorry, excuse me.
楚門  這位是慧雲
Uh, Truman, this is Vivien. Vivien, this is Truman.
你們會經常見面
The two of you are gonna be neighbors.
嗯
Oh.
我的意思是...
I guess what I'm...
生命脆弱
What I'm saying is that, Uh, life is...fragile.
- 慧雲  你的辦公室 - 對不起
- Vivien, your office. - Sorry.
什麼? 對不起...
What's that? Oh, I'm sorry. Uh...
真的? 好極了
You do? Oh, great.
我記下你的資料
Uh, let me take your information.
二號機準備  播二號
Ready 2. Go to 2.
再用中鏡
And back to medium.
然後...廣鏡
And wide.
我正想訓練這小子...
I was just trying to train the kid to...
他在地下室幹什麼?
What's he doing in the basement?
美露走後  他搬了下去
He moved down there after Meryl packed up and left.
他有突發的舉動  該向我報告
Why wasn't I told? Any unpredictable behavior has to be reported.
我以為... 他在睡覺
Uh, he...he's just sleeping, I thought.
可以看得清楚點嗎?
This the best shot we've got?
- 你想看什麼? - 時鐘攝影機呢?
- What's to see? - What's on the clock cam?
被東西擋著
It's an obstruction...Obstruction.
他在地下室做過什麼?
What happened down there?
收拾垃圾  我本想通知你
He was just tidying up his garbage. I was gonna call you
但他沒收拾完就睡著了
But halfway through he gave up, and he fell asleep.
- 我要檢查明天的... - 明天的保險會
- I wanna check on the setups for the... - insurance convention tomorrow.
幹得好
Nice move.
現在開始
There you go.
對準音響  拍攝他的身體
Isolate the audio. Give me a closeup on his torso.
有呼吸
He's still breathing.
- 歌露 - 在 - 打電話給他
- Where's Chloe? - Yes, sir. - Call him.
- 說些什麼? - 說打錯了
- What do you want me to say? - Tell him it's a wrong number.
為什麼那麼久?
What took you so long?
要輪候
Just had to wait for it.
客人多  你的
They were busy. Here.
- 什麼事? - 不知道
- What's going on? - I don't know. They're...
他進房  站著  沒做什麼
He came down into the room. He did nothing but stand around for a while.
閉嘴  觀察
Shut up and watch it!
然後我們就用夜鏡
Then we went to nightvision.
他睡著了
He's asleep.
- 這裡  停! - 什麼事?
- There! Stop it! - What?
- 放大 - 哪裡?
- Zoom in. - On which?
椅子下
Under the chair there.
加強清晰度
Enhance it.
- 是不是... - 不得了
- Is it...Oh. Chloe - Oh, my god.
他不可能在樓上  一定在那裡
I...if...he couldn't have gone up the stairs. I definitely...he must still be in the room.
- 叫馬龍去 - 知道
- Get Marlon over there. - Right away.
楚門! 有驚喜!
Truman! Surprise party!
老朋友 六罐冰凍啤酒等待你我享用
Oh. Come on, buddy. I got a 6-pack of cold brewskis with our name on them.
你在哪裡? 還不出來?
Come on, pal. Come on, buddy.
糟了!
Shit!
馬龍  找他  他還在房裡
Marlon, find him. He's still in the room.
不要躲了  出來吧
Come out, come out wherever you are.
好  這語氣就對了
That's good. Keep it light.
我知道你在這裡  我會找到你
I know you're in here. I'm gonna find ya.
搜桌子下麵
Check under the table.
你後面的衣櫃
The closet, behind you.
他究竟在哪裡?
Gee. I wonder where he could possibly be.
草地鏡頭  用草地鏡頭
The lawn cam, get me the lawn cam.
不要看鏡頭  繼續說話
Don't look in the camera. Say something. Keep it going. Keep it going.
他走了
He's gone.
- 停播! - 停播?
- Cut transmission! - Cut transmission?
停播!
Cut it!
有沒有搞錯
Jesus! God in heaven!
- 漆黑一片 - 把電話給我
- Everything's black. - Give me the phone.
(技術故障  請稍候)
不知道他在哪裡 但一定已經逃遠了
I don't know where he is, but he's gone.
所有配角都在搜索他
We've got every available extra looking for him.
要角也在幫忙
Uh, the principals are helping out.
台前幕後都出動  搜遍每一角
The crew, too, so every sector's covered.
- 道具車有沒有少了? - 沒有
- What about prop cars? - Yes, they've been accounted for.
他必定走路
He has to be on foot.
全世界都認得他  他跑不掉
He has the world's most recognizable face. He can't disappear.
搜他出來 搜他出來 乖狗!
Go. Hunt him. Hunt him. Yeah. Go find him, Pluto. Good dog! Good dog!
大陣容
All this fuss.
他聽到我的聲音  就會出來
If he could just hear my voice.
楚門!
Truman! Truman!
我試試叫他
Let me try.
楚門! 是爸爸! 有事找我商量!
Truman! It's me! Dad! Let's talk!
我知道
Yeah, I know.
我們搜過廣場
Just about done with the square.
他一定在巴厘摩處  回去搜吧
Got to go back to barrymore, Check the interiors. He's got to be in there.
巴厘摩?
Barrymore, huh?
- 學校呢? 誰去? - 不知道
- Uh-huh. But what about the college? Who's watching that? - I don't know.
- 派人去吧 - 知道
- Send somebody over there, Ok? - All right.
立即帶個人去?
Take another man and get down there now, all right?
一定要把那雜種抓出來
I don't give a damn. Just find the son of a bitch.
拿電池來  黑漆漆怎找到他?
Get some batteries. This guy's Not gonna glow in the dark. Just get'em down here.
不知發生什麼事  接過來我這裡
I don't know what's going on. Reroute it back to me.
太暗了  不可能找到他
We need more light. We'll never find him this way.
現在幾點?
What time is it?
日出太早了
It's way too early for that.
準備日出
Cue the sun.
幾點?
Jeez! What time is it?
克裡斯多夫  什麼事?
Christof, What's going on?
有傳聞說他死了
Did you know that there's a rumor circulating that he's dead?
聽到嗎? 記者蜂擁而至
You hear me? The media is having a feeding frenzy over this.
人人都打電話來
All the phone lines are jammed,
所有電視臺都播馬龍出醜鏡頭
And every network has a pirated shot of Marlon making an ass of himself in front of the camera.
贊助商威脅要取消合約
The sponsors are threatening to rip up their contracts.
取消? 現在停播  收視率也很高
Why? We're getting higher ratings with this graphic than we've ever had on this show.
他無蹤無影
No sign of him.
馬龍  你回來  跟其他人會合
Why don't you head back to town and join the others?
大家留在原位  知道嗎?
Everyone else is at first positions, Ok?
謝了
Thank you.
大家留在原位了嗎?
Everyone's at first positions, right?
他一定還沒走
We've got the light. So he's got to be there somewhere.
我們沒有留意海面
We're not watching the sea.
等一下 為什麼要留意海面?
Hang on a minute. Why would we watch the sea?
搜索海港
Sweep the harbor.
啟動海港攝影機 將鏡頭接去電腦
Bring up the harbor cameras. Shift all harbor cameras to computer, please.
有些攝影機失靈?
Some of those are out, aren't they?
四部失靈  但燈塔那個有效
Yeah. We have 4 of them down, but we have the lighthouse cameras up.
- 開動水上攝影機 - 什麼事?
- All buoy cams, please. - What's happening?
- 長鏡 - 為什麼搜索水面?
- Ok. Long lens, short base cameras. - Why are we looking at the water?
好  移動它
Pan it, will you, please?
楚門
Truman
你去哪裡?
Where are you going?
他是做保險的  怎懂得駕駛船?
How can he sail? He's in insurance.
他不怕水嗎?
Isn't he terrified of the water?
恢復播映...
Resume transmission...
Resuming transmission...
二賠一  我賭他溜不掉
I got 2 to 1 he doesn't make it. Hey, I want a piece of that. 2 to 1 he doesn't make it.
車匙留在車內
Just leave 'em in the car.
輕點聲
Shh.
別用船杆鏡  看不見他的臉
Let's get off this mast shot. We can't see his face.
- 用船艙鏡 - 船艙鏡
- Go to the cabin cam. - Cabin cam.
好極
There. Perfect.
拍到我們的英雄了
That's our hero shot.
派另一艘船出去
Let's get another boat out there.
起士  我要跟碼頭的人通話
Ok. Listen, gus, I need you to talk to the guys on the ferry.
快點  快點出發
Come on. Get it moving. Get it out of here.
快些
Come on.
我只是巴士司機
I'm just a bus driver.
他們不懂得駕駛船
Bottom line is, they can't drive the boat.
他們都是演員
They're actors.
怎樣截停他?
How do we stop him?
好吧...
Ok, uh...
開動風浪程式
We're going to be accessing the weather program now.
大家準備好
So hold on to your hats.
知不知道?
You got that?
把風暴集中在船上
No. I think we're gonna want to localize the storm over the boat.
要對準船的位置
You can get the coordinates for that.
他沒有救生艇  應付不來
There's no rescue boat. He won't know what to do.
他會害怕  會駛回來
He'll turn back. He'll be too afraid.
風暴來了
There she blows.
(起動掣)
來吧
Come on.
閃電
Give me some lightning.
再閃!
Again!
Hit him again!
收手  全世界都在看著
For god's sake, Christof, the whole world is watching.
不能讓他當眾死掉
We can't let him die in front of a live audience.
他當眾出生
He was born in front of a live audience.
楚門!
Truman!
你做得到的!加把勁!
You can do it! Hold on!
你還有什麼法寶?
Is that the best You can do?
你想阻擋我  只有殺我
You're gonna have to kill me!
- 我命令你停播 - 繼續播
- On behalf of the studio, I demand that you cease transmission. - Keep running.
晨早遇到一個醉水手 問你怎麼辦?
What shall we do with a drunken sailor early in the morning?
加強風力 加強風力
Increase the wind. Increase the wind!
我最後警告你
I'm telling you for the last time.
- 有多接近? - 很接近
- How close is he? - Very.
- 吹翻他  吹他落海 - 去你的
- Capsize him. Tip him over. - Damn you, Christof!
- 他把自己綁著船身! - 閉嘴!
- You can't. He's tied himself to the boat! - Shut up!
他連浸死也不怕
He's gonna drown, and he doesn't even care.
吹翻他!
Do it. No. Do it!
夠了
That's enough.
天啊
Oh.
我想跟他談談
I want to talk to him.
(出口)
楚門
Truman.
你可以說話
You can speak.
我聽得到你
I can hear you.
你是誰?
Who are you?
我是創造者
I am the creator of a television show
創造了一個 受萬眾歡迎的電視節目
That gives hope and joy and inspiration to millions.
那麼  我是誰?
Then who am I?
你就是那個節目的明星
You're the star.
什麼都是假的?
Was nothing real?
你是真的
You were real.
所以才有那麼多人看你
That's what made you so good to watch.
聽我勸告
Listen to me, Truman.
外面的世界...
There's no more truth out there...
跟我給你的世界一樣的虛假
than there is in the world I created for you.
有一樣的謊言
The same lies.
一樣的欺詐
The same deceit.
但在我的世界...
But in my world...
你什麼也不用怕
You have nothing to fear.
我比你更清楚你自己
I know you better than you know yourself.
你無法在我腦內裝攝影機
You never had a camera in my head.
你害怕
You're afraid.
所以你不能走
That's why you can't leave.
楚門  不要緊  我明白
It's Ok, Truman. I understand.
我看了你的一生
I have been watching you your whole life.
你出生時  我在看你
I was watching when you were born.
你學走路時  我在看你
I was watching when you took your first step.
你入學  我在看你
I watched you on your first day of school.
還有你掉第一顆牙齒那一幕
The episode when you lost your first tooth.
你不能離開  楚門
You can't leave, Truman.
上帝  求求你
Please, god.
你屬於這裡...
You belong here...
你可以走出去
You can do it.
跟我一起吧
with me.
回答我
Talk to me.
說句話
Say something.
你他媽的說句話! 你上了電視了
Well, say something, goddamn it. You're on television.
正在向全世界直播
You're live to the whole world.
假如再碰不見你...
In case I don't see you...
祝你早 午 晚都安
Good afternoon, good evening, and good night.
耶
Yep.
歐耶!歐耶!
Yeah! Yeah!
他做到了 他做到了
He did it. He did it.
他做到了! 他做到了!
He did it! He did it!
他走脫了! 走吧! 楚門!
He made it! Yeah! All right, Truman!
停播
Cease transmission.
Ceasing transmission.
- 要多一片嗎? - 不要了
- You want another slice? - No. I'm Ok.
- 還有什麼節目? - 看看還有什麼 - 還有什麼節目? - 看看還有什麼 電視預告尼?
- What else is on? - Let's see what else is on. Where's the TV guide?